Kaylie Young

New Lenox, IL 60451 dk.young.72@gmail.com +1 801 696 6239

Backend focused web developer recently graduated from Austin Coding Academy's Javascript Fullstack Program.

Hard working tech enthusiast, skilled in critical thinking and problem solving. Moved to higher skill hardware support team within 6 months. Skilled in effectively communicating technical problems and steps to reproduce and find potential solutions for said problems.

Strong ability to learn and apply new concepts quickly. Good understanding of C# and Python, in addition to using tools such as Visual Studio and Unity.

Strong ability to teach myself new skills and use creative thinking to achieve my goals.

Background in speech and debate, using that skill set to produce in depth research and verify information that is used in projects.

Willing to relocate to: Denver, CO

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

Work Experience

Backend Developer Intern

Ripple Learning LLC-Austin, TX September 2023 to November 2023

Working on developing a Job Application Tracking Web Application. My primary focus is backend development, working on login utilizing Auth0 and structuring and managing user databases for potential tracked job applications.

Hardware Support Specialist

Sitel Group-Orem, UT September 2021 to April 2022

Worked as a Hardware Support Specialist on the Playstation Contract Project's PS5 support team.. Received calls from consumers that needed assistance troubleshooting problems with their PS5 hardware. The job requires quick critical thinking, problem solving, and effective communication to relay instructions and troubleshooting steps to consumers to perform over the phone. Quickly moved up to the higher skilled support team within 6 months.

FC Associate

Amazon.com-Salt Lake City, UT September 2020 to August 2021

Outbound graveyard shift associate making sure that packages get onto pallets, gaylords, and carts to then be transported to other facilities. Responsibility included being an ambassador, or trainer, for new-

hires and cross-trained warehouse associates. Trailer-Dock-Release, or TDR, trained, in addition to being an operator of select robotic systems on the warehouse floor.

Captioning Agent

CaptionCall-Orem, UT April 2020 to September 2020

Responsibilities include captioning phone calls for individuals with impaired hearing.

Education

Certificate of Course Completion in Full Stack Javascript Application Development Program

Austin Coding Academy - Austin, TX November 2022 to August 2023

High school diploma in General Studies

Green River Community College - Auburn, WA August 2017 to May 2019

High school diploma in General Studies

Tahoma Senior High School - Maple Valley, WA August 2015 to May 2019

Skills

- Warehouse Experience (1 year)
- Shipping & Receiving (1 year)
- Computer skills (10+ years)
- Customer service (2 years)
- · Logistics
- Packaging
- Freight Experience
- RF Scanner
- Critical Thinking
- Interpersonal Skills
- Conflict Resolution
- Empathy
- · Load & Unload
- Video editing (1 year)
- Technical Support
- C#
- Python
- Unity
- Technical support (Less than 1 year)

- Visual Studio
- HTML5
- Creative writing (3 years)
- Research (6 years)
- Writing skills (10+ years)
- React (1 year)
- JavaScript
- Git
- MySQL
- Application Development
- Python
- Databases
- APIs
- RESTful API (2 years)
- REST
- Software development
- Application development
- Node.js
- C#
- SQL
- Visual Studio
- CSS
- HTML5
- OOP
- Customer service